<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>UBC ThunderBikes</title>
	<atom:link href="./index.html" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>./../index.html</link>
	<description>Powering the Future of Racing: Join UBC ThunderBikes in Building High-Performance Electric Motorcycles</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Sun, 24 Nov 2024 05:53:34 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=6.7.1</generator>

<image>
	<url>./../wp-content/uploads/2024/11/icon-logo.png</url>
	<title>UBC ThunderBikes</title>
	<link>./../index.html</link>
	<width>32</width>
	<height>32</height>
</image> 
	<item>
		<title>2024 Year End Report</title>
		<link>./../2024/05/08/boosting-social-media-for-enhancing-business-2/index.html</link>
					<comments>./../2024/05/08/boosting-social-media-for-enhancing-business-2/index.html#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[down1037]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 08 May 2024 06:35:49 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Yearly Update]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://demo.blockskit.com/agency/?p=192</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Year in Review: UBC ThunderBikes 2023-2024 This year has been one of ambition, growth, and resilience for UBC ThunderBikes. Our team tackled significant challenges head-on and celebrated remarkable milestones that reflect our dedication to innovation in electric motorcycle racing. Achievements Building Sparky: Our SM24 Bike Sparky, our flagship project, is the culmination of countless engineering [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p class="has-primary-color has-text-color has-link-color has-x-large-font-size wp-elements-1dccd6d8af4a9c5fc935db445ecd4b70"><strong>Year in Review: UBC ThunderBikes 2023-2024</strong></p>



<p>This year has been one of ambition, growth, and resilience for UBC ThunderBikes. Our team tackled significant challenges head-on and celebrated remarkable milestones that reflect our dedication to innovation in electric motorcycle racing.</p>



<hr class="wp-block-separator has-alpha-channel-opacity is-style-wide"/>



<h3 class="wp-block-heading"><strong>Achievements</strong></h3>



<h4 class="wp-block-heading"><strong>Building Sparky: Our SM24 Bike</strong></h4>



<p>Sparky, our flagship project, is the culmination of countless engineering hours and collaboration across disciplines. By the end of June 2024, we achieved a race-ready design, competing at the AHRMA Laguna Seca motorsport event. Though unforeseen transportation damage prevented Sparky from racing, we proudly returned with accolades, including the award for Best Design in the Formula Lightning category.</p>



<h4 class="wp-block-heading"><strong>Engineering Highlights</strong></h4>



<ul class="wp-block-list">
<li><strong>Battery Innovations</strong><br>We iterated on our battery modules to enhance safety and performance, emphasizing hands-on prototyping and interdisciplinary teamwork. Our design culture fosters technical growth for all members, enabling skills in simulations, manufacturing, and industrial standards.</li>



<li><strong>Battery Management System (BMS)</strong><br>Our BMS integration allowed real-time feedback on cell health, voltage, and temperature. This advancement highlighted our commitment to safety and efficient energy management.</li>



<li><strong>Sub-Frame Design</strong><br>This unique component replaced traditional motorcycle designs to house high-voltage elements securely. Hundreds of hours were invested in its research, modeling, and assembly, ensuring safety and structural integrity.</li>



<li><strong>Aerodynamics and Materials</strong><br>We advanced our expertise in vacuum bag wet layup processes, refining aerodynamics with precision CNC-machined molds. Our aero team demonstrated excellence in both design and craftsmanship.</li>
</ul>



<h4 class="wp-block-heading"><strong>Competition Experience</strong></h4>



<p>Despite setbacks, our participation in the AHRMA Laguna Seca event allowed us to showcase our designs, network with industry professionals, and identify opportunities for future enhancements. Recognition for &#8220;Most Unique Bike&#8221; and design excellence further validated our efforts.</p>



<hr class="wp-block-separator has-alpha-channel-opacity is-style-wide"/>



<h3 class="wp-block-heading"><strong>Challenges</strong></h3>



<p>The year wasn&#8217;t without its hurdles. Transportation-related damage resulted in a significant financial and emotional setback, affecting critical components like the motor, batteries, and BMS. However, this experience strengthened our resolve to innovate further and rebuild with superior components.</p>



<hr class="wp-block-separator has-alpha-channel-opacity is-style-wide"/>



<h3 class="wp-block-heading"><strong>Future Goals</strong></h3>



<p>Looking ahead, we aim to elevate our designs for the 2025 AHRMA competition in Pittsburgh. Key objectives include:</p>



<ul class="wp-block-list">
<li>Optimized battery integration for improved balance and performance.</li>



<li>Redesigning the sub-frame and cooling systems for efficiency and reliability.</li>



<li>Developing custom PCB circuitry and sleek, functional display units.</li>



<li>Enhancing aerodynamics through advanced manufacturing techniques.</li>
</ul>



<p>Budget estimates place heavy emphasis on competition-related expenses and advanced design work, reflecting our commitment to excellence.</p>



<hr class="wp-block-separator has-alpha-channel-opacity is-style-wide"/>



<h3 class="wp-block-heading"><strong>Gratitude</strong></h3>



<p>Our successes this year would not have been possible without the unwavering support of our sponsors and community. Your contributions have empowered us to grow as engineers and innovators, pushing the boundaries of what our team can achieve.</p>



<div class="wp-block-uagb-image uagb-block-438351c5 wp-block-uagb-image--layout-default wp-block-uagb-image--effect-static wp-block-uagb-image--align-none"><figure class="wp-block-uagb-image__figure"></figure></div>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>./../2024/05/08/boosting-social-media-for-enhancing-business-2/feed/index.html</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
